Karen Majewski collection CPAA 10.11
Connecticut Polish American Archives
Karen Majewski collection
1981-1990
CPAA 10.11
Connecticut Polish American Archives
1.0 Linear feet
Material in the collection was compiled by Karen Majewski for her graduate studies project. It includes interviews with refugees from Poland from the Solidarity immigration wave in 1980's, as well as extensive collection of newspaper clippings related to the subject.
Majewski, Karen
Biographical/Historical note
The collection consists of material compiled by Karen Majewski, a graduate student, who worked on a Solidarity émigré project. Ms. Majewski interviewed refugees from Poland, who came to the United States during the so called Solidarity immigration wave at the beginning of 1980's. Additionally Karen Majewski collected hundreds of clippings from various Polish language newspapers, from 1981-1989, related to immigration issues.
Arrangement note
Material in the collection is arranged by title and chronologically by date.
Scope and Contents note
The collection consists of audio tapes with interviews and transcriptions. It includes hundreds of clippings from mostly Polish and Polish American press related to immigration in 1980's. Interviews are in English and clippings in Polish, except few from the English language periodicals.
Clippings.; Interviews; NSZZ "Solidarność" (Labor organization); Poland -- Emigration and immigration; Polish people -- United States
- Interviews, 1989-1990; The series contains audio tapes with interviews and transcribed interviews.
  - Karen Majewski collection - letter about donating the collection to the Connecticut Polish American Archives in 2010. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alicja Sadkowski, Ann Arbor, MI., October 27, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Wlodzimierz Wielbut, Ann Arbor, MI, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Piotr Westwalewicz, Ypsilanti, MI, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Jerzy Petryniak, Ann Arbor, MI, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Jan Krawiec, Chicago, IL, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Barbara Delwska McQuaid, Ann Arbor, MI, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Kasia Kietlinska, Ann Arbor, MI, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Andrzej Dolata, Ann Arbor, MI, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Henryk Szaniawski, Ann Arbor, MI, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Audio tapes with interviews: Andrzej & Krystyna Dolata, Zbigniew Robakiewicz, Kasia Kietlinska, Piotr Westwalewicz, Jerzy Petryniak, Marek Mintek, Stanislaw Lisiewski., 1989 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- News clippings, 1982-1990; This series contains clippings from Polish-American and American newspapers related to refugees from Poland in 1980's. Clippings are organized by a title and a year. Clippings which were read and translated are marked as done.
  - Nowy Dziennik Polish Daily News (done), 1983-1988 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Nowy Dziennik Polish Daily News (not done), 1982 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Nowy Dziennik Polish Daily News (not done), 1983 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Nowy Dziennik Polish Daily News (not done), 1984 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Nowy Dziennik Polish Daily News (not done), 1985 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Nowy Dziennik Polish Daily News (not done), 1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Nowy Dziennik Polish Daily News (not done), 1987 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Nowy Dziennik Polish Daily News (not done), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Nowy Dziennik Polish Daily News (not done), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Nowy Dziennik Polish Daily News (not done), 1990 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Dziennik Polski Polish Daily News (done), 1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Dziennik Polski Polish Daily News (not done), 1982 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Dziennik Polski Polish Daily News (not done), 1983 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Dziennik Polski Polish Daily News (not done), 1984 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Dziennik Polski Polish Daily News (not done), 1985 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Dziennik Polski Polish Daily News (not done), 1986 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Dziennik Polski Polish Daily News (not done), 1987 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Dziennik Polski Polish Daily News (not done), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Dziennik Polski Polish Daily News (not done), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Dziennik Polski Polish Daily News (not done), 1990 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Dziennik Zwiazkowy (done), 1985-1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Dziennik Zwiazkowy (not done), 1982 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Dziennik Zwiazkowy (not done), 1983 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Dziennik Zwiazkowy (not done), 1984 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Dziennik Zwiazkowy (not done), 1985 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Dziennik Zwiazkowy (not done), 1986 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Dziennik Zwiazkowy (not done), 1987 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Dziennik Zwiazkowy (not done), 1988 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Dziennik Zwiazkowy (not done), 1989 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Gwiazda Polarna (done), 1982-1988 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Gwiazda Polarna (not done), 1982 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Gwiazda Polarna (not done), 1983 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Gwiazda Polarna (not done), 1984 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Gwiazda Polarna (not done), 1985 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Gwiazda Polarna (not done), 1986 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Gwiazda Polarna (not done), 1987 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Gwiazda Polarna (not done), 1988 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Gwiazda Polarna (not done), 1989 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Detroit News, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Kultura, France, 1985-1988 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Pomost, Chicago, IL, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Puls, United Kingdom, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Relax, Chicago, IL, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Kontakt, France, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Misc. articles in Polish, 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Christian Science Monitor, 1981-1987 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - New York Times, 1982-1987 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Washington Post, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Chicago Tribune, 1982-1989 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Misc. articles in English, 1982-1987 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - "Sila kraju emigracja" article by E.J. Osmanczyk, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 31)